Guide to the Peter Palmquist Collection of Humboldt County, California, Male Photographers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Peter Palmquist collection of Humboldt County, California, male photographers
1850-2003
1973-2003
WA MSS S-2670
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
53.12
(160 boxes) + 3 broadside folders
The collection includes information about and examples of the work of male amateur and commercial photographers, studio assistants, photographic processors, colorists, photojournalists, film makers, and film theaters collected by Peter Palmquist from 1971 until his death in 2003. The collection documents the practice and occupation of photography in Humboldt County, California, from around the incorporation of the county in 1853. This collection consists of biographical files collected by Palmquist for over nine hundred men and businesses involved in photography and photographic materials that represent the work of nearly three hundred individuals and firms. Individual photographers with significant quantities of material in the collection include Ray Jerome Baker, Augustus William Ericson, Amasa Plummer Flaglor, Alexius Alexander Holmes, N. B. Strong, and Joshua P. Vansant. Firms with substantial groups of material in the collection include the Arcata Union newspaper, Art-Ray Company, Freeman Art Co., and Seely Studio.
Palmquist, Peter E.
Baker, Ray Jerome, 1880-1972
Ericson, A. W. (Augustus William), 1848-1927
Flaglor, Amasa Plummer, 1848-1918
Holmes, Alexius Alexander, 1865-1922
Strong, N. B.
Vansant, Joshua P., 1861-1950
Art-Ray Company
Freeman Art Co
Seely Studio
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Peter E. Palmquist on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 148-160: Restricted Fragile Materials. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Biographical information and photographic materials related to women photographers active in Humboldt County, California, are included in Peter Palmquist Collection of Women in Photography (WA MSS S-2600). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Books and periodicals formerly in the personal library of Peter Palmquist are accessible via the library catalog by conducting an advanced search of special collections with the search string: "Palmquist, Peter E., Ownership."
Peter E. Palmquist (1936-2003)
A photographer, collector, and historian of photography, Peter Eric Palmquist was born in Oakland, California on September 23, 1936. In 1944, he moved with his family to Ferndale, California, and he spent most of his life in Humboldt County. During adolescence, Palmquist trained himself in photography. He served in the United States Army as a photographer from 1955 to 1959, mainly with the Supreme Headquarters Allied Powers Europe in Paris, France. Palmquist worked briefly as a photographer for the state government of California from 1959-1961. From 1961 until his retirement in 1989, Palmquist worked as a staff photographer for Humboldt State University, Arcata, California, where he also graduated with a Bachelor of Arts degree in Art in 1965.
From 1971 until his death, Palmquist collected textual materials and hundreds of thousands of photographic items documenting the practice and occupation of photography from its beginning through the turn of the twenty-first century. He had particular interests in early California photographers, photographers of the American West, and women photographers.
A self-trained researcher and historian of photography, Palmquist organized more than a hundred exhibitions and wrote more than three hundred articles and a hundred monographs. He was a founding editor of The Daguerreian Annual; president of the National Stereoscopic Association.
Palmquist died January 13, 2003, in Oakland.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes information about and examples of the work of male amateur and commercial photographers, studio assistants, photographic processors, colorists, photojournalists, film makers, and film theaters collected by Peter Palmquist from 1971 until his death in 2003. The collection documents the practice and occupation of photography in Humboldt County, California, from the incorporation of the county in 1853. This collection consists of biographical files collected by Palmquist for over nine hundred men and businesses involved in photography and photographic materials that represent the work of nearly three hundred individuals and firms. A database http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/palmquist_humboldt/ provides individual name access to men with biographical files, as well as any available information regarding their aliases, working locations, life dates, and work dates. Individual photographers with significant quantities of material in the collection include Ray Jerome Baker, Augustus William Ericson, Amasa Plummer Flaglor, Alexius Alexander Holmes, N. B. Strong, and Joshua P. Vansant. Firms with substantial groups of material in the collection include the Arcata Union newspaper, Art-Ray Company, Freeman Art Co., and Seely Studio.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Biographical Files, 1971-2003. II. Photographic Materials, circa 1850-2003.
Union (Arcata, Calif.); Photographers -- Biography; Photographers -- California; Photographers -- West (U.S.); Photography -- Bio-bibliography; Photography -- California; Photography -- West (U.S.); Photography, Artistic; Photographers -- Bio-bibliography; Photographers -- Miscellanea; Photographers -- Pictorial works; Photographers -- History; Photographers; California -- Pictorial works; Humboldt County (Calif.); Humboldt County (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Biography files; Negatives (photographs); Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Slides (photographs); Transparencies; Baker, Ray Jerome, 1880-1972; Ericson, A. W. (Augustus William), 1848-1927; Flaglor, Amasa Plummer, 1848-1918; Holmes, Alexius Alexander, 1865-1922; Palmquist, Peter E.; Strong, N. B.; Vansant, Joshua P., 1861-1950; Art-Ray Company; Freeman Art Co; Seely Studio
- Biographical Files, 1971-2003; Series I; 5.42; (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This series is intellectually arranged alphabetically by personal or corporate name. The physical arrangement compiles smaller quantities by individuals and firms in the same box. while others are housed in one or more boxes.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of biographical files and volumes that document over nine hundred men and firms involved with photography in Humboldt County, California, from 1853 to 2003. Palmquist and his assistants compiled much of the material from secondary sources between 1971 and 2003.
  This portion of the finding aid provides access to ranges of boxes holding hundreds of individual biographical files. Researchers may also consult a database http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/palmquist_humboldt/ that provides individual name access to men and firms represented in this series, as well as any available information regarding their aliases, working locations, life dates, and work dates.
  The contents of individual biographical files range from a single sheet providing the name of a man or firm to more comprehensive information, such as his life and work dates and his working locations, as well as professional or personal acquaintances.
  Related Archival Materials note
  Biographical information related to women photographers active in Humboldt County, California, are included in Peter Palmquist Collection of Women in Photography (WA MSS S-2600).
  - Albertype Co., to Bass, Thomas (Box 1)
  - Bear Photo Service to Catton, Steve (Box 2)
  - Cempa, Joe, to Dilling, Albert? (Box 3)
  - Dobbyn and Johnston to Fletcher, Harrell (Box 4)
  - Foales to Gyse, Henry (Box 5)
  - Hadley, Craig L., to Investment Photographs (Box 6)
  - J. C. Penney and Company to Lykins, Guy (Box 7)
  - M. C. Robelet and Co. to Mitchell, Edward H. (Box 8)
  - Mobley, Paul T., to Petty, Charles (Box 9)
  - Phegley, John W., to Scotia Camera Club (Box 10)
  - Sears, Paul, to Studio 3B Productions (Box 11)
  - Sudden Service Photo to Ulrich, Lawrence C. (Box 12)
  - Vaissade, Benjamin J., to Zook's News Agency (Box 13)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1850-2003; Series II; 47.7; (145 boxes)
  Series II is organized into five subseries: Photographic Materials; Photograph Albums, Oversize Photographic Materials; Glass Negatives and Transparencies; and Film Negatives.
  This series consists of photographic materials collected by Palmquist that were created by or document individual male photographers or photographic firms.
  This series consists of vintage photographic prints, as well as a significant quantity of copy photographs created by Palmquist of vintage photographic prints. The series documents the breadth of work by male photographers in Humboldt County from the middle of the nineteenth century to the late twentieth century. Works by a photographer may appear in multiple subseries.
  For most of the listed photographers, the collection has only a few photographs. However, there are significant quantities of photographs by Ray Jerome Baker, Augustus William Ericson, Amasa Plummer Flaglor, Alexius Alexander Holmes, N. B. Strong, and Joshua P. Vansant. Firms with significant quantity of material in the collection include the Arcata Union newspaper, Art-Ray Company, Freeman Art Co., and Seely Studio.
  Specific dates of materials or image creation dates were not captured during processing.
  Nearly all of the individuals and firms with photographic materials in this series have biographical files in Series I.
  Photographic materials related to women photographers active in Humboldt County, California, are included in Peter Palmquist Collection of Women in Photography (WA MSS S-2600).
  - Photographic Materials
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by the surname of the photographer or the corporate name of the studio followed by photographs by unidentified photographers.
    This subseries consists of vintage photographic prints, copy photographs, 35 millimeter color slides, photographic negatives, associated publications, and ephemera. Photographic materials with dimensions larger than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.) are located in the Oversize Photographic Materials subseries.
    - Albertype Co. (Box 14)
    - Aldrich, Clarence U. (Box 14)
    - Alford, W. B. (Box 14)
    - Allen's Art Studio (Box 14)
    - Altpeter, Louis (Box 15)
    - Anderson, Hugh (Box 14)
    - Anderson, Jack W. (Box 14)
    - Antón, Don Gregorio (Box 14)
    - Arcata Photograph Gallery (Box 14)
    - Arcata Union (Newspaper)
      Photographs and negatives from the Arcata Union newspaper are arranged into two groupings acccording to format, and then roughly chronologically.
      Biographical/Historical note
      The Arcata Union was a weekly newspaper that published from 1886 to 1995 in and for the city of Arcata, California
      - Photographs
        - 1954-1972 (unsorted) (Box 16)
        - 1968-1971 (Box 17)
        - 1970-1984 (sports) (Box 18)
        - 1972 (Box 19)
        - 1973 (Box 20)
        - 1974 (Box 21)
        - 1975 (Box 22)
        - 1976 (Box 23)
      - Negatives
        - 1977 (Box 24)
        - circa 1950-1960 (Box 25)
        - circa 1950-1960 (Box 26)
        - circa 1950-1960 (Box 27)
        - circa 1950-1960 (Box 28)
        - circa 1950-1960 (Box 29)
        - circa 1960-1969 (Box 30)
        - circa 1965-1972 (Box 31)
        - 1964-1969 July (Box 32)
        - 1969 August-1970 September (Box 33)
        - 1971-1972 March (Box 34)
        - 1972 April-December (Box 35)
        - 1973 January-October (Box 36)
        - 1973 November-1974 July (Box 37)
        - 1974 August-1975 May (Box 38)
        - 1975 Jun-1976 March (Box 39)
        - 1976 April-December (Box 40)
        - 1977 January-July (Box 41)
        - 1978 June-1982 October (Box 42)
        - circa 1978-1982, undated (Box 43)
        - circa 1979-1982 (sports) (Box 44)
        - 1982 February-1984 April (sports) (Box 45)
    - Arnoff, Mark (Box 14)
    - Art Photo Studio (Box 14)
    - Art-Ray Company (Box 46, Box 47)
    - Atkinson and Woods (Box 14)
    - Ayers (Box 14)
    - Baker, Ray Jerome (Box 48, Box 49)
    - Barber, William Bradbury (Box 14)
    - Bardell, J. C. (Box 14)
    - Bear Photo Service (Box 14)
    - Beche, W. (Box 14)
    - Beers and Benbow (Box 14)
    - Bergeron and Gatliff (Box 50)
    - Bergeron, Jay P. (Box 51)
    - Bestor, Tom (Box 14)
    - Blacketer, DeWayne (Box 14)
    - Bliler, Harry A. (Box 14)
    - Blum, Robert Frederick (Box 14)
    - Boslaw, Clarence C. (Box 14)
    - Boston, David (Box 14)
    - Bridal Boutique and More (Box 14)
    - Bunnell, Schuyler Ulysses (Box 14)
    - Burgess, Austin Ami (Box 14)
    - Burrill, W. L. (Box 14)
    - C. O. Liberty and Co. (Box 52)
    - California. Division of Highways (Box 52)
    - Calvert, R. J. and Co. (Box 52)
    - Cameo Art Studio (Box 52)
    - Canclini, Peter (Box 52)
    - Canepa, Peter M. (Box 52)
    - Cardinell-Vincent Company (Box 52)
    - Cary and Co. (Box 52)
    - Catton, Steve (Box 52)
    - Chamley, Stephen Fred (Box 52)
    - Chappelle, Jerry (Box 52)
    - Chase and Co. (Box 52)
    - Chase, Alexander Wells (Box 52)
    - Chase, Edwin S. (Box 52)
    - Cherry, Edgar (Box 53)
    - Clearwater, Robert William (Box 52)
    - Clements, E. F. (Box 52)
    - Colburn, Anthony Thomas (Box 52)
    - Cooke, Norman W. (Box 52)
    - Cooper, Ed (Box 52)
    - Cooper, Thomas Joshua (Box 52)
    - Copsey, Jack E. (Box 52)
    - Corbett, John L. (Box 52)
    - Couse-Baker, Robert (Box 52)
    - Cousins, George W. (Box 52)
    - Creative Eye Studio (Box 52)
    - Crippen and Cardoza (Box 52)
    - Crippen, George Wesley (Box 52)
    - Curt Teich Company (Box 52)
    - Curtis, Edward S. (Box 52)
    - Daly Brothers (Box 54)
    - Davidson, Norvalle Rice (Box 54)
    - Davies and Ericson (Box 54)
    - De Pierre, A. (Box 54)
    - DeBuhr, Joseph R. (Box 54)
    - Decker, Howard (Box 54)
    - Deu Vaul, Bert E. (Box 54)
    - Dickinson and Bell (Box 54)
    - Dill, Douglas L. (Box 54)
    - Dold, Lewis (Box 54)
    - Donnel, James Warren (Box 55)
    - Dowe, Oscar S. (Box 56)
    - Duning, Richard A. (Box 54)
    - Eastern Illustrating and Publishing Co. (Box 57)
    - Eastern Studio (Box 57)
    - Eastman Studios (Box 57)
    - Eddy (Box 57)
    - Elite Studio (Box 57)
    - Ellis (Box 57)
    - Ellis, John T. (Box 57)
    - Ericson, Augustus William (Box 58, Box 59)
    - Ericson, Edgar Waldo (Box 57)
    - Eriksen, Martin (Box 57)
    - Eureka Chamber of Commerce (Box 57)
    - Eureka News Company (Box 57)
    - Eureka Photo and Art Co. (Box 57)
    - Eureka Printing Co. (Box 57)
    - Falk, Herm (Box 60)
    - Farrington, Thomas H. (Box 60)
    - Fassold, Peter (Box 60)
    - Fetrow, W. P. (Box 60)
    - Finan, Michael A. (Box 60)
    - Fishbaugh, W. A. (Box 60)
    - Fitzgerald, Clifton E. (Box 60)
    - Flaglor and Gregor (Box 60)
    - Flaglor, Amasa Plummer (Box 61, Box 62)
    - Flanders and Tuttle (Box 60)
    - Fortuna Camera Club (Box 60)
    - Foster, Virgil (Box 60)
    - Frahman, Herbert H. (Box 60)
    - Freeman Art Co. (Box 63, Box 64)
    - Freese and Fetrow (Box 65)
    - Frye and Smith (Box 60)
    - FVN Corporation (Box 60)
    - Gallo, Rick (Box 66)
    - Gatliff and Thompson (Box 67, Box 68)
    - Gatliff, Bertram (Box 69)
    - George H. Eberhardt and Company (Box 60)
    - Gilchrist, Neil F. (Box 60)
    - Gilfillian, Adam W. (Box 60)
    - Gillard, Rudolf Karl (Box 60)
    - Gillick Printing Inc. (Box 60)
    - Goldsby, Michael W. (Box 60)
    - Grant, Martin Howe (Box 70)
    - Gregor, Alexander (Box 60)
    - Greun?, Jerry (Box 60)
    - Grist, C. M. (Box 60)
    - Gyse, Henry (Box 60)
    - H. S. Crocker and Company (Box 71)
    - Hadley, Craig L. (Box 71)
    - Hakanson, Peter Erik (Box 71)
    - Harrison Company (Box 71)
    - Hart, Don (Box 71)
    - Harwood (Box 71)
    - Hazeltine, Leland S. (Box 71)
    - Hemenway (Box 71)
    - Hennies, Frank (Box 71)
    - Hennings, Barry (Box 71)
    - Hess, Edward A. (Box 71)
    - Hess, Guy Ovel Roylsten (Box 72)
    - Hilgeman, Charles (Box 71)
    - Hills, C. W. (Box 71)
    - Hoefler, Paul Louis (Box 71)
    - Holmes, Alexius Alexander (Box 73, Box 74)
    - Hough, Earl Burton (Box 71)
    - Houston and Howland (Box 71)
    - Howell, A. N. (Box 71)
    - Huestis, W. F. (Box 71)
    - Hughes, O. J. (Box 71)
    - Humboldt Photo Studio (Box 71)
    - Humboldt State University (Box 75)
    - Humboldt Studio (Box 71)
    - Intersimone, Angelo (Box 71)
    - Jackson, W. A. (Box 71)
    - Johnson, Charles Wallace Jacob (Box 71)
    - Johnson, Craig C. (Box 76)
    - Kaeser and Blair (Box 77)
    - Keir, Walter (Box 77)
    - Ketner News Agency (Box 77)
    - Keystone View Company (Box 77)
    - KIEM-TV (Box 77)
    - Kilburn, Kenneth Clyde (Box 78)
    - King, Howard (Box 77)
    - Klein, Ron (Box 77)
    - Knight, Thomas L., Jr. (Box 77)
    - Knowles, Albert C. (Box 77)
    - Korb, Vern (Box 79)
    - Kuykendall, Frank (Box 77)
    - Lange, William (Box 80)
    - Larson, Selma (Box 80)
    - Lavoie, Rex (Box 80)
    - Laws (Box 80)
    - Long, Addington (Box 80)
    - Lowman, Hubert (Box 80)
    - M. C. Robelet and Co. (Box 80)
    - Martin, E. Frank (Box 80)
    - Martin, Ron (Box 80)
    - Mastercraft Post Card Co. (Box 80)
    - Mayer, Fred (Box 80)
    - McCloskey, James J. (Box 80)
    - McCurry Foto Co. (Box 80)
    - McKeown, Jerry (Box 80)
    - McMillan Brothers (Box 80)
    - McMillan, Wesley James (Box 81)
    - McNeil, William Abraham (Box 80)
    - McNew, Lon (Box 80)
    - Meiser, Jesse A. (Box 82)
    - Meline, R. (Box 80)
    - Menefee, Peter Mason (Box 80)
    - Meriden Gravure Company (Box 80)
    - Metivier, Charles (Box 80)
    - Miller and Chase (Box 83)
    - Miller, Don (Box 83)
    - Miller, George W. (Box 83)
    - Mills, C. H. (Box 83)
    - Mitchell, Edward H. (Box 83)
    - Modern Photo Studio (Box 83)
    - Moot, Jeff (Box 83)
    - Moulin, Gabriel (Box 83)
    - Muybridge, Eadweard James (Box 83)
    - New York Gallery (Box 83)
    - Newman Postcard Co. (Box 83)
    - Noble, Skelton Stanford (Box 83)
    - Nowell, Tom (Box 83)
    - NYCE Manufacturing Co. (Box 83)
    - Osborne, A. W. (Box 83)
    - Otto's Pharmacy (Box 83)
    - Owings, J. J. (Box 83)
    - Pacific Novelty Company (Box 84)
    - Parr, G. H. (Box 84)
    - Patterson, Frank (Box 85)
    - Perrott, Crestus E. (Box 84)
    - Petersson, Lowell Malcolm (Box 84)
    - Phegley, John W. (Box 84)
    - Phillips, Denver (Box 84)
    - Photo Specialty Shop (Box 84)
    - Pillsbury Picture Co. (Box 84)
    - Polychrome Co. (Box 84)
    - Proctor's Photo Lab and Photographic Engineering Center (Box 86)
    - Quality Snapshot Co. (Box 87)
    - Quinby, Lewis Ward (Box 87)
    - Rands Bros. (Box 87)
    - Redwood Empire Association (Box 87)
    - Redwood Empire Photographic Service (Box 87)
    - Redwood Studio (Box 87)
    - Rex's (Box 87)
    - Roberts, Mike (Box 87)
    - Root, W. H. (Box 87)
    - Ross (Box 87)
    - Rotograph Co. (Box 87)
    - Sawyers Photographic Services (Box 88)
    - Scenic Art (Box 88)
    - Scenic View Card Co. (Box 88)
    - Seely Brothers (Box 89, Box 90, Box 93)
    - Seely Studio (Box 94, Box 95)
    - Shaw, Seth Louis (Box 88)
    - Shipley, J. W. (Box 88)
    - Shomaker, Leo (Box 88)
    - Shoreline Productions (Box 88)
    - Shull, Darrell (Box 88)
    - Shultz, Maury (Box 88)
    - Shuster, Merle (Box 88)
    - Siipola, John (Box 88)
    - Smith News Company (Box 88)
    - Smith, A. T. (Box 88)
    - Smith-Western Co., Inc. (Box 88)
    - Stammer, Ronald (Box 88)
    - Stark, Alexander J. Zan (Box 88)
    - Stevens, Leonard (Box 88)
    - Stowe, C. K. (Box 88)
    - Stringfield, Alfred Moore (Box 88)
    - Strong, N. B. (Box 96, Box 97, Box 98)
    - Strong, W. K. (Box 88)
    - Suhr, Charles F. (Box 88)
    - Svensson, Bo (Box 88)
    - Swain, George R. (Box 88)
    - Swanlund Studio (Box 99)
    - Swanlund, David Harper (Box 100)
    - Swanlund, Oscar William (Box 101)
    - Swanlund, Sam (Box 102)
    - Tapp, Carlan (Box 103)
    - Thonson, William H. (Box 103)
    - Thorobred Photo Service (Box 103)
    - Tibbetts, H. C. (Box 103)
    - Toll, William B. (Box 103)
    - Tollman and Crippen (Box 103)
    - Tollman and McMillan (Box 103)
    - Tollman, John W. (Box 103)
    - Toms, James (Box 103)
    - Towne, Paul D. (Box 103)
      - Framed photographic print (Box 104)
    - Tracy, Joe (Box 103)
    - Trainor, Joe B. (Box 103)
    - Tuttle and Johnson (Box 103)
    - Ulrich, Lawrence C. (Box 105)
    - Union Oil Company of California (Box 105)
    - United States Coast Guard (Box 105)
    - United States. Army. Corps of Engineers. (Box 105)
    - Van Burkleo and Lambert (Box 105)
    - Van Burkleo, Leroy (Box 105)
    - Van de Mark, Dave (Box 105)
    - Vansant, Joshua P. (Box 106, Box 107, Box 108)
    - Vansant, William P. (Box 105)
    - Walpole, Ray E. (Box 105)
    - Walters, Vern (Box 105)
    - Wax, William (Box 105)
    - Weidner, Charles (Box 105)
    - Western Air Photo (Box 105)
    - Western Ways, Inc. (Box 105)
    - Weyman, Mark (Box 105)
    - White Glove Photo Service (Box 105)
    - Wolfe, Francis B. (Box 105)
    - Woodmen of the World (Box 105)
    - Woods, Richard (Box 105)
    - Wulzen, Albert H. (Box 105)
    - Wunderlich Brothers (Box 109)
    - Wyckoff, John (Box 105)
    - Zook's News Agency (Box 105)
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - Panoramic photographs of Humboldt Bay and the surrounding area by an individual photographer (Box 110)
      - Places
        Photographic prints by discrete photographers arranged geographically by subject of the photographic print.
        - Arcata (Box 111)
        - Blue Lake (Box 111)
        - Briceland (Box 111)
        - Bridgeville (Box 111)
        - Bull Creek (Box 111)
        - Clam Beach (Box 111)
        - Eel River (Box 111)
        - Essex (Box 111)
        - Eureka (Box 111)
        - Ferndale (Box 111)
        - Fortuna (Box 111)
        - Garberville (Box 111)
        - Hoopa Valley (Box 111)
        - Humboldt Bay (Box 111)
        - Humboldt Redwoods State Park (Box 111)
        - Hydesville (Box 111)
        - Klamath River (Box 111)
        - Mad River (Box 111)
        - Metropolitan (Box 111)
        - Orleans (Box 111)
        - Port Kenyon (Box 111)
        - Redwood Creek (Box 111)
        - Redwood Highway (Box 111)
        - Samoa (Box 111)
        - Scotia (Box 111)
        - Shelter Cove (Box 111)
        - Shively (Box 111)
        - Trinidad (Box 111)
        - Van Duzen River (Box 111)
        - Unidentified locations (Box 111)
      - Identified subjects
        Photographic prints by discrete photographers arranged by identified individuals, families, or firms
        - Averill, Dunbar, and Lucinda Averill (Box 112)
        - Barber family of Bayside (Box 112)
        - Clarke, Cecile (Box 112)
        - Eel River and Eureka Railroad Company (Box 112)
        - Gephart, Lewis Eugene (Box 112)
        - Gist, Arthur (Box 112)
        - Hammond and Little River Redwood Company, Ltd. (Box 112)
        - Humboldt Oil Company (Box 112)
        - Jewett, Arthur N. (Box 112)
        - Kuskila family of Eureka (Box 112)
        - Liska family of Eureka (Box 112)
        - Mathewson, E. (Box 112)
        - MacMillan family (Box 112)
        - Metcalf, Franki, and Mattie Heosmer (Box 112)
        - Sanders family (Box 112)
        - Simpson family of Eureka (Box 112)
        - Sousa, George J. (Box 112)
        - Stephens family of Bayside (Box 112)
        - Strongs, Robert, and Ernest Strongs (Box 112)
        - Turner, Dennis (Box 112)
        - Zehndner, John Jacob (Box 112)
        - Unidentified (Box 112)